Kathryn Beals papers, 1927-1928, 1976, 1994
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Kathryn Beals papers 1927-1928, 1976, 1994
MS 440
Beals, Kathryn
Papers and Photographs, 1927-1928, 1979, 1994. This collection contains correspondence, photos, newspaper clippings, and ephemera of Kathryn Beals, including two letters to her sister from acquaintances upon Kathryn’s death in 1976. The bulk of the collection consists of correspondence with her family and ephemera she collected while touring with the Peters-Wright vaudeville dance troupe for 15 months in 1927-1928.
.75 linear ft
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Kathryn Beals was born on August 1907 and raised in San Francisco, California. Between 1927 and 1928 she spent 15 months touring the United States with the Peters-Wright vaudeville dance troupe The Wright Dancers. During this time she exchanged letters and photos with her mother, father, uncle, and sister, Carol. When she was not performing or rehearsing she visited tourist sites like the Niagara Falls, Coney Island, and Washington, D.C. In the collection there are photos of these trips. The collection includes some of the theater programs on which she appears for presentations in Boston, New York, and Houston. She also attended plays, musicals, movies. She attended the opening of musicals like Funny Face with Fred and Adele Astaire to which we have the theater program. The letters were kept by her mother and later entrusted to her sister. Don Langley later wrote the book Vaudeville Days with these letters.
During her vaudeville days she suffered a knee injury that would affect her for the rest of her life. In 1929 she married Rolland Langley. Ten months later she gave birth to the first of her three children. Years later they divorced. In 1943 she contracted an illness similar to polio and was confined to a wheelchair for the rest of her life. On October 27, 1976 she passed away.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into two series.
Series I: Correspondence, 1927-1928, 1976
Series II: Personal, 1927-1928, 1994
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains correspondence, photos, a film, newspaper clippings, and ephemera of Kathryn Beals from the years 1927 to 1928 and two letters to her sister from acquaintances upon Kathryn’s death in 1976. Between the years 1927 to 1928 she toured with the Peters-Wright vaudeville dance troupe. During this time she wrote diligently to her close family members about the cities, theaters, sites, famous people she met, and daily experiences she had away from home. The letters are organized chronologically. There is also a typed version of most of the correspondence.
Access Terms
Beals, Kathryn
Correspondence
Entertainers--United States
Photographs
Theaters—United States
Vaudeville
Container List
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1927-1928; 1976
  This series is arranged chronologically by date. It contains the correspondence between Kathryn Beals and her close family members from 1927-1928 and two letters sent to her sister after she passed away.
  - Correspondence, 1927 March-April (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1927 May-July (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1927 August-September (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1927 October-November (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1927 December; 1928 January (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1928 February-March (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1928 April-May (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1928 June-July; 1928 November; 1928 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence-typed, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Undated correspondence, ca. 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Series 2: Personal, 1927-1928; 1994
  This series is organized by subject. It contains photos, a film, and ephemera collected during 1927-1928 and the copyright registration of the book Vaudeville Days by Kathryn Beals with Don Langley
  - Address book and expenses sheet, ca. 1927-1928 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - G4 Guest Ranch brochure, ca. 1928 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Copyright registration of book Vaudeville Days, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1927-1928 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Portrait photos of Kathryn Beals, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Photos and postcards, 1927-1928 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Theater programs in which Kathryn Beals appears, 1927-1928 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Programs of musicals, movies, Plays, and concerts attended by Kathryn Beals, 1927-1928 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 8mm film, ca. 1927-1928 (Box 2, Folder 9)